http://www.rinovelty.com/policies/privacy

Catalogs
Login
Cart
(0)
Home> Policies> Privacy Policy
Information You Provide.
E-mail Addresses.
Mailing Addresses.
Sharing Information.
Access to Customer Information.
Children.
How do we protect visitor information?
Do we use 'cookies'?
Third Party Disclosure
California Online Privacy Protection Act
How does our site handle ‘Do Not Track’ signals?
Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?
Contacting Us
This Privacy Policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their Personally Identifiable Information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect, or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.
Information You Provide.
Information You Provide. Rhode Island Novelty receives, stores and uses the information you provide us. You provide us with your name, address, phone number, email address, credit card information and other information when you do such things as place an order, enter a contest or giveaway, sign up for promotional emails, request a catalog or make use of other aspects of our website. That information is used to communicate with you, process your order, administer contests or giveaways, provide catalogs or provide other information that you request, collect payment for products and services you purchase, respond to your questions, customize your shopping experience and otherwise with your consent or as permitted and required by law. We may also use this information to send you information about other products and services that you may be interested in.
Go to Top
E-mail Addresses.
We do not rent, share, or exchange our customers' email addresses (except as described in paragraph 8 below), but we do use these addresses for our own promotional email marketing. You can opt out of receiving promotional emails anytime. Instructions on how to opt out are included in every promotional email or you may opt out here.
Go to Top
Mailing Addresses.
Your mailing address may be added to our paper catalog mailing list. In that event, you may receive Rhode Island Novelty catalogs or other catalog titles affiliated with Rhode Island Novelty. From time to time, that mailing list may be shared, rented or exchanged with other responsible businesses. If you do not want your name shared with businesses not affiliated with Rhode Island Novelty, or if you do not want to receive our catalogs, please call 1-800-528-5599 or fax 1-800-448-1775. Please allow 2-4 weeks to process your request.
Go to Top
Sharing Information.
Except as noted above, we may share information about our customers in a variety of ways. We share customer information among the businesses affiliated with www.rinovelty.com. We may share customer information with merchants whose websites link with ours. We may also employ other businesses or consultants to perform functions such as sending mail or email, analyzing data and customer lists, processing accounts receivable, marketing or other functions. In those situations, third parties will have access to customer information for the purpose of performing their functions. Though we do not rent, share or exchange customer email addresses in the ordinary course of business, we may sell, transfer or assign customer information in connection with a merger, consolidation, sale of assets or similar business transaction. We may disclose your personal information to a third party advertising partner and its service providers. The information we disclose may include your transactional information with us. Our advertising partner makes the data we provide anonymous and does not use your personal information such as your name, address, and email address to deliver advertising to you that is tailored to your interests. To choose not to have your transactional information given to, or used by, our third-party advertising partner in this way, click here.
Go to Top
Access to Customer Information
Customers can update their billing information by accessing their account in the My Account section at rinovelty.com. There is also an email address update link in every promotional email you receive from us.
Go to Top
Children
Rhode Island Novelty does not sell products for purchase by children. Although we sell products intended for use by children, those products are intended for purchase by adults. If you are under 18, you may use RhodeIslandNovelty.com only with permission of or supervision by a parent or guardian.
Go to Top
How do we protect visitor information?
We use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards.
We use an SSL certificate.
We implement security measures when a user:
places an order.
enters, submits, or accesses their information.
We use a payment gateway provider for authorization and security.
Go to Top
Do we use 'cookies'?
Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved service. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences in the future.
In summary, we use cookies to:
More effectively retain information regarding the items in the shopping cart process.
Keep track of advertisements.
Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.
You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You can do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is different as it pertains to cookies.  Look in your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookie settings.  If you disable cookies, some features of our site will be disabled. You will still be able to place orders, but some of the speed, features, and functionality of the ordering process may be compromised.
Go to Top
Third Party Disclosure
Third Party Disclosure. To the extent permitted by law, we may also receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information. For example, we sometimes receive updated delivery and address information from our shippers or other sources so that we can correct our records and deliver your next purchase or communication more efficiently.
Go to Top
California Online Privacy Protection Act
According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:
Users can visit our site anonymously.
Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or at a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy', and can be easily be found on the page specified above.
Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes
On our Privacy Policy page.
Users are able to change their personal information:
By emailing us.
By calling us.
By logging in to their account.
Go to Top
How does our site handle ‘Do Not Track’ signals?
We honor them and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.
Go to Top
Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?
This site uses a tracking technology called Google Analytics to obtain site usage information such as users’ Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, internet domain and host names, browser software, and the date and time that the site is visited. Data obtained through Google Analytics does not include and is not linked to any personal information. Data from Google Analytics allows us to monitor the use of this site, understand how users find our site, and improve the site’s functionality and content.  Our use of Google Analytics is in compliance with Google’s Terms of Service.
Google provides more information about Google’s privacy practices and information on how to opt - out of Google Analytics tracking of your web browsing.
This website may use the Google AdWords remarketing service to advertise on third party websites (including Google) to previous visitors to our site. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven’t completed a task on our site, for example using the contact form to make an inquiry. This could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to our website. Of course, any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy and Google’s privacy policy.
You can set preferences for how Google advertises to you by using the Google Ad Preferences page, or you can opt out of interest-based advertising entirely by cookie settings, or by permanently using a browser plugin.
Go to Top
Fair Information Practices
In order to be compliant with Fair Information Practices, we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:
• We will notify the users via email within seven business days
• We will notify the users via on site notification within seven business days
• We comply with the Individual Redress principle, which provides individuals the right to pursue legal against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. Additionally this principle allows for individuals to seek recourse against data collectors through means of government agencies.
Go to Top
CAN SPAM Act
We collect your email address:
To send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
To process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders.
We may also send you additional information related to your product and/or service.
For marketing purposes and customer follow-up regarding completed transactions.
To be accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:
We will not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
We will include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
We will monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
We will provide an 'opt-out' or 'unsubscribe' option.
We will provide an 'opt-out' or 'unsubscribe' option (instructions appear on the bottom of each email).
We will honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests in a timely manner.
Go to Top
Copyright and Trademark Information
Entire contents of this website Copyright © Rhode Island Novelty, Inc. All rights reserved.
Rhode Island Novelty (RINCO) and the Rhode Island Novelty logo are trademarks of Rhode Island Novelty, Inc. in the U.S. and other countries. The absence of a product or service name or logo from this list does not constitute a waiver of Rhode Island Novelty trademark or other intellectual property rights concerning that name or logo.
Rhode Island Novelty’s trademarks may be used publicly only with permission from Rhode Island Novelty. Fair use of Rhode Island Novelty’s trademarks in advertising and promotion of Rhode Island Novelty’s products requires proper acknowledgement.
Other product or brand names may be trademarks or registered trademarks of their respective holders.
Updated 27 August 2014
Go to Top
Changes to our Privacy Policy
We reserve the right to amend the Privacy Policy at any time, for any reason, without notice to you, other than the posting of the amended Privacy Policy on this website. You should check our website frequently to see the current Privacy Policy that is in effect and any changes that may have been made to it. The provisions contained herein supersede all previous notices or policies regarding our privacy practices that govern the use of this Website.
Go to Top
Contacting Us
If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us in writing or email using the information below.
Rhode Island Novelty, Inc.
© 2019 Rhode Island Novelty. All Rights Reserved.  Terms & Conditions | Privacy Policy |  Sitemap
